Ryan L. Brooks

(704) 562-6121 | ryanbrooks99@gmail.com | 2005 Thurston Dr, Indian Trail, NC 28079

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ryanbrooks0101
GitHub: https://github.com/ryanbrooks99

Portfolio: https://ryanbrooks99.github.io/reactportfolio/

CAREER SUMMARY

Thorough, established business professional with 14+ years of banking industry experience and certified full stack web developer striving to apply technical skills towards building functional client and server-side applications. Strategic problem solver with the persistence necessary to execute goals.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Agile, Scrum, AJAX, MVC, JSON, TDD, Postman, React, OOP, MongoDB, Mongoose, VS Code, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, UI Kit, jQuery, Git, Bash, GitHub, GitLab, REST APIs, Node.js, ES6, Express, MySQL, Handlebars, ORM, Sequelize, Heroku, NPM, Granim, Microsoft Office

PROJECTS

EquiPPE | https://vast-ravine-19894.herokuapp.com/

Application allows users to login, register an account, and purchase PPE equipment via an online shopping cart.

- Full-stack developer
- Technologies: React, React Bootstrap, MySQL, Sequelize, Sweet Alert

MusiQuery | http://project-2-agrc.herokuapp.com/

Application allows artists to search for networking opportunities with other artists and industry professionals.

- Full-stack developer
- Technologies: HTML, Bootstrap, API routes, Sequelize, Express, Passport, Granim

CockTell Me | https://oksimone.github.io/cocktellme/

Application allows users to take personality assessment then be paired with perfect cocktail based on results.

- Front-end developer
- Technologies: HTML, UI Kit, API

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

AVP; Relationship Administrator II: Bank of America, Charlotte, NC - August 2014 - Current

- Recipient of Bronze award for 100% accuracy on portfolio audit
- Manage portfolio of multimillion-dollar credit facilities for commercial real estate investors and developers
- Develop close relationships with title and escrow companies on closing transactions, payoffs, refinances, and to order date down endorsements, review of as-built surveys and other new construction related documents
- Analyze and process funding of complex construction draw requests including disbursements for CAPEX, TI/LC, and FF&E
- Communicate daily with clients to deliver comprehensive reporting on general loan inquiries including timing of draw funding, taxes, insurance, and covenant requirements
- Continual research and monitoring of client's total risk exposure (TRE)
- Strengthen trust and rapport by developing strong relationships with clients
- Improve system of record data integrity and covenant compliance through detailed analysis and interpretation of complex loan documentation

AVP; Payoff Department Team Leader; Client Relations Manager: Bank of America, Charlotte, NC - February 2010 - August 2014

- Managed private portfolio of 200+ commercial mortgages
- Team leader and interim department manager; oversaw delegation of assignments, as well as training and mentoring teammates
- Regarded as Subject Matter Expert for payoff and lien release related inquiries
- Developed and implemented process improvements which improved efficiency of department
- Mitigated risk through review and approval of payoff statements calculated by team members

ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

Payoff Department Analyst: Bank of America, Charlotte, NC - Oct 2007 – Feb 2010 Financial Statement Analyst: Bank of America, Charlotte, NC – Sept 2006 – Oct 2007

EDUCATION

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development – October 2020 University of North Carolina-Charlotte

Bachelor of Arts, Business Administration – December 2003 University of North Carolina-Wilmington